# **Krzysztof Achinger**

L10n and i18n QA Lead at Symbio, Project Manager at Bohan, Translator and Interpreter, China Business Consultant

achingerpl@gmail.com

## Summary

#### Experienced in:

- I18n and l10n QA testing
- Team leading
- Innovative solution driven approach
- Translation and localization
- Interpretation
- Lexicography
- Web and mobile apps development
- Supporting communication in international business (Poland China)

#### Characteristics:

- Relaxed and friendly
- · Open-minded and hardworking
- Doer
- Responsible and punctual
- Multilingual
- Flexible and reasonable

Currently leading international team of 110n and i18n QA testers, running thousands of manual and automated test cases on webapps and mobile financial industry software. Helping the team to grow and mature by providing product knowledge support and tools' training.

Co-author and co-founder of Bohan; responsible for technical side of the project, translates chengyu and develops entries for the Bohan Dictionary. Spends a good deal of time translating works of literature ("Wolf Totem" by Jiang Rong and "Call to Arms" by Lu Xun are waiting to be published). In 2009/10 collaborated with Beijing Foreign Studies University and The Commercial Press (####) on "Obrazkowy s#owniczek j#zyka chi#skiego" (Chinese Little Picture Dictionary) and "Obrazkowy s#ownik j#zyka chi#skiego" (Chinese Picture Dictionary). At the same time he also translated a textbook for learning Chinese (published by Hanban in 2010 in Beijing).

Provides communication bridge between Polish and Chinese entrepreneurs serving as translator, interpreter and advisory body.

Graduated from Near and Far Eastern Studies at the Jagiellonian University, after graduation moved to China

for two years to study Chinese at the Beijing Foreign Studies University. Then obtained Master's Degree in Chinese Studies from University of Leeds.

## Experience

### L10n and i18n QA Lead for PayPal at Symbio

November 2013 - Present (10 months)

- Designing end-to-end 110n and i18n oriented test cases
- Leading team of international testers in testing new features and product regression testing
- Enhancing cooperation between manual and automated testing teams
- Troubleshooting testing environment (staging and tools)
- Communicating with the client and reporting

#### Co Founder at Bohan.pl

February 2010 - Present (4 years 7 months)

- Managing projects for online dictionary, mobile apps
- Supervising volunteers
- Translations and translation service outsourcing
- Consulting for Polish-Chinese entrepreneurs wishing to establish business relations
- Publishing materials for studying Chinese

1 recommendation available upon request

#### Freelance Translator at Freelance Translator

March 2009 - Present (5 years 6 months)

- Chinese-Polish-English translation and interpretation
- Website localization, manuals, technical and ordinary texts
- Fluent in CAT tools

#### On-site i18n QA Lead for PayPal at Symbio

August 2013 - November 2013 (4 months)

- On-site delivery team and i18n QA team consultation and communication
- Providing feedback about client's needs and requirements to the "home team"
- Mitigating time/resource issues
- Reporting testing progress and developing testing tactics

#### L10n QA Tester and Lead for PayPal (Mobile and Web apps) at Symbio

September 2011 - October 2013 (2 years 2 months)

- Testing localized version of PayPal Mobile and Web apps (multiplatform)
- Designing localization test cases
- Leading team of international testers in testing new features and product regression testing
- Communicating with the client and reporting

#### Chairman at China Alliance of Polish Students

#### November 2009 - August 2012 (2 years 10 months)

China Alliance of Polish Students was a non-profit organization bringing together Polish students, who tied their academic adventure with China.

#### **Publications**

#### Wspó#czesny j#zyk chi#ski

Sinolingua January 1, 2010 Authors: Krzysztof Achinger

Wspó#czesny j#zyk chi#ski zosta# stworzony dla studentów, których j#zykiem ojczystym jest j#zyk polski. Celem tego podr#cznika jest rozwini#cie w studencie zdolno#ci rozumienia i komunikowania si# w j#zyku chi#skim. Rozwija on w szczególno#ci umiej#tno#ci s#uchania, mówienia, czytania i pisania po chi#sku.

#### Obrazkowy s#ownik j#zyka chi#skiego

The Commercial Press January 1, 2010

Authors: Krzysztof Achinger

15 rozdzia#ów tematycznych; 142 podrozdzia#y dotycz#ce róznych aspektów #ycia codziennego; ponad 4000 powszechnie u#ywanych s#ów ilustrowanych obrazkami lub zdj#ciami; indeksy wszystkich wyrazów wyst#puj#cych w s#owniku - po chi#sku i po polsku; tradycyjna pisownia ka#dego znaku w indeksie wyrazów chi#skich.

#### Chi#ski obraz #wiata na podstawie idiomów dotycz#cych pieni#dzy i bogactwa

Foreign Language Teaching and Research Press 2012

Authors: Krzysztof Achinger

Article in: Spotkania Polonistyk Trzech Krajów - Chiny, Korea, Japonia, rocznik 2010/2011

#### Obrazkowy s#owniczek j#zyka chi#skiego

Foreign Language Teaching and Research Press January 1, 2009

Authors: Krzysztof Achinger

Seria Obrazkowych s#owniczków j#zyka chi#skiego powsta#a po to, by u#atwi# uczniom opanowanie s#ownictwa j#zyka chi#skiego przy u#yciu ciekawych ilustracji. Obrazkowy s#owniczek j#zyka chi#skiego zosta# zaprojektowany z my#l# o m#odym odbiorcy i skierowany jest do uczniów szkó# podstawowych oraz gimnazjów.

## **Projects**

#### **Bohan Dictionary**

March 2009 to Present

Members: Krzysztof Achinger, Marek Jachymski, Marlena Achinger, Cindy Xi, Justyna Yuntong Li, S# Polish-Chinese and Chinese-Polish online dictionary.

#### **Bohan Android**

#### April 2011 to Present

#### Members:Krzysztof Achinger, #ukasz Tokarski

Polish-Chinese and Chinese-Polish dictionary for Android.

#### **Bohan iOS**

2012 to Present

Members: Krzysztof Achinger, Karol Wawrzyniak, Marek Jachymski

Polish-Chinese and Chinese-Polish dictionary for iOS.

#### **Bohan Windows Phone**

2013 to Present

Members:Krzysztof Achinger, #ukasz Tokarski

Polish-Chinese and Chinese-Polish dictionary for Windows Phone.

### Languages

Chinese(Professional working proficiency)Polish(Native or bilingual proficiency)English(Professional working proficiency)

#### Certifications

### **ISTQB - BCS Certified Tester Foundation Level**

BCS, The Chartered Institute for IT License 990443595 March 2013

#### Education

#### **University of Leeds**

Master's Degree, Chinese Studies, 2010 - 2011

#### **Beijing Foreign Studies University**

General Student, Chinese Language and Literature, 2008 - 2010

#### **Jagiellonian University**

Bachelor's Degree, Middle and Far Eastern Cultural Studies, 2005 - 2008

#### **Interests**

Rock climbing, archery and any other outdoor sports, rock music, Asia with special emphasizes on China, cloud computing fan, reading

## Skills & Expertise

**Software Project Management** 

**Technical Translation** 

Localization

**Localization Testing** 

**Computational Linguistics** 

Chinese

**Business in China** 

**Publishing** 

**Online Publishing** 

**Software Development** 

**Quality Assurance** 

**Data Quality** 

**Software Quality Assurance** 

**Interpreter** 

**Import** 

**Project Management** 

**Translation** 

**Interpreting** 

Internationalization

**Chinese culture** 

**International Relations** 

**Intercultural Communication** 

**English** 

Mandarin

**Foreign Languages** 

Multilingual

**Language Teaching** 

Globalization

**China Business Development** 

**Simultaneous Interpretation** 

**Website Localization** 

**Proofreading** 

**Polish** 

#### Courses

#### **Independent Coursework**

PADI Discover Scuba Diving

First Aid Rescuer

Drivers License (Polish and Chinese)

# Volunteer Experience

# Translator at Racjonalista.pl

2009 - 2011 (2 years)

Translating popular science English to Polish texts.

# **Krzysztof Achinger**

L10n and i18n QA Lead at Symbio, Project Manager at Bohan, Translator and Interpreter, China Business Consultant

achingerpl@gmail.com



# 1 person has recommended Krzysztof

"I have worked with Krzysztof on several projects, he has proven to be very conscientious person and a real doer who gets down to things immediately and never rests before the project is completed."

— Marek Jachymski, Freelance Translator, Freelance translator, worked directly with Krzysztof at Bohan

Contact Krzysztof on LinkedIn